☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
2008年12月23日
Everyone get close to everyone so you can touch someone.
‎大家都靠近点 挨紧点
This is very serious. It's more serious than you can imagine.
情况十分严重 比你们想象得还要严重
Let's pray.
‎我们开始祈祷
Father, we thank you for...
‎感谢天父…
just being our God, and for all that you do.
‎成为我们的神 ‎感谢您所做的一切
We thank you for this day, and...
‎感谢您赐予的今天 并且…
we thank you for the chill in this air, Father.
感谢您赐予空气中的寒冷 天父
Because we thank you for the sunshine,
‎因为我们感谢您赐予了阳光
because you create the chill and you create the sunshine.
‎因为您创造了寒冷 您也创造了阳光
And you know these are tough times, Father.
‎天父啊 您知道这段时间 我们经历着艰难困苦
We're asking this morning for your guidance.
‎今早 我们请求您的指引
- Amen. - Amen.
‎-阿门  ‎-阿门
We stand here today, uh, with a plant that's closing,
‎今天 我们站在这里 和将要关闭的工厂一起
with a... a deep, rich history,
‎这家工厂历史深厚
and, uh, it's sad for me and, I'm sure, everybody else in there to see it go,
‎站在这里看着它关闭 ‎我很难过 我相信其他人也很难过
but I will say this:
‎不过 我会这么说
I'm extremely proud of the people that work in this plant here.
我以在这里辛苦奉献的工人为傲
There's none better.
‎他们是最棒的工人
They know how to get the job done.
‎他们尽职尽责
♪ 多少人曾爱慕你年轻时的容颜 ♪
♪ 多少人曾在生命中来了又还 ♪
♪ 可知一生有你 都陪在你身边 ♪
- How old are these houses?  - Two hundred years?
‎-你说它这房子有多少年  ‎-应该有一两百年感觉
No way! America was founded only 200 years ago.
乱讲 美国 美国建国才一两百年好不好
-Then at least several decades.  - Yeah, maybe.
‎‎-美国建国才两百年 几十年我觉得  -几十年吧
- Cold? - Yeah.
‎-冷不冷  ‎-冷
But this is really beautiful.
‎但是很漂亮
Yeah, gorgeous.
‎是啊 真的非常漂亮
See, America's airspace is really busy.
‎你看 其实美国上空 ‎上面那个 其实航空空路都非常繁忙
There's one.
‎那有一架飞机
- And there.  - Mmm.
‎-那边有架飞机  -对
俄亥俄州代顿市通用汽车工厂关闭后 ‎当地裁减超过一万个工作岗位
2010年 中国公司开始增加对美国制造业的投资 重启美国倒闭工厂
朝着前途无量的职业迈出第一步
When you take a look at an automobile,
当你们看到一辆汽车
you see glass all around it.
你们会看到很多玻璃
That's what we do.
‎我们工厂就是做这个的
We have about 70% of the market.
汽车玻璃这个市场上 我们占了七成
Okay? Which is pretty extensive.
‎明白吗 这是相当庞大的市场份额
We have facilities around the world,
‎我们在世界各地都有工厂
throughout China, United States now, with our plant here.
‎中国各地都有 现在我们在美国也开设了工厂
What we're doing is we're melding two cultures together:
‎我们正在融合两国文化
the Chinese culture and the US culture.
‎中国文化和美国文化
So we are truly a global organization.
‎所以我们是一个真正的国际组织
So, we do have three different shifts right now that we are working with.
‎现在 我们实行三班倒的轮班制
A first, second, and a third. Pretty traditional.
‎早班 中班和夜班 挺传统的
You'll also have a 30-minute unpaid lunch.
你们还会有30分钟的不带薪午餐时间
Plus, there's two 15-minute paid breaks.
此外还有15分钟的带薪休息时间
Plenty of opportunities, ladies and gentlemen.
机会多多 各位女士们 先生们
Plenty of opportunities.
‎机会多多
Is this a union shop?
这家‎工厂有工会吗
We are not.
没有
It is our desire to not be.
‎我们不希望工会化
But we recognize that, one, we need to do things right by employees.
不过我们很清楚 我们需要善待员工
Okay? We recognize that.
好吗 我们会保证这一点
- I have, actually, 28 years experience.  - Very good.
‎-我有28年工作经验  ‎-很好
Payroll, human resources, operations, things like that.
‎工资单 人力资源 运营 这种
I have a master's
‎我还有机械工程的
- in mechanical engineering too, so...  - Okay, good. Super.
‎-硕士学位 所以…  ‎ -好 非常好
- Sounds like you got a lot of good skills.  - Well, I... Actually, I've worked
‎-听起来你掌握了多种技能  ‎-我其实…
- in all kinds of different levels of...  - Yeah? Okay, good.
‎-在每个层级都工作过…  ‎-是吗 很好
What we'll do is we'll take a look at your résumé. All right?
‎我们会查看您的简历 好吗
Where you sit today used to be a General Motors plant.
‎现在 你们所坐的位置 ‎曾经是通用汽车的工厂
This plant closed,
‎这家工厂关闭了
leaving 2,000 families unemployed.
‎导致两千个家庭失业
And now, there are over 1,000 employees working here,
‎现在 一千多名员工在这工作
with still more to be hired.
我们还会招更多人
It was a little over two years ago that this facility was a very dark
‎两年前  这里的通用汽车工厂是一个非常暗黑
and very stark reminder of the greatest economic downturn
‎又非常鲜明的标志 提醒着人们铭记美国历史上
in American history since the Great Depression.
‎自大萧条以来 遭遇的最大的经济衰退
And with that, you understand the... the personal impact that that has,
‎从那件事中 大家都知道 ‎通用汽车对个人的影响‎
individually and for the families of all those involved.
以及对所有相关家庭产生的影响
It's been a very fast process from the very beginning.
‎这里一开始就发展得非常迅速
When I hired in, there was nothing in the plant.
‎我进厂的时候 厂里什么都没有
And since that time, you can see, in the last six months,
从那之后 你可以看到 最近半年来
the amount of people and equipment that have come in.
‎进厂的人员和设备数量大大增加
And it's, uh, exciting.
这进展很令人兴奋
The commitment everybody's put in, hard work.
‎大家积极投入 辛勤工作
Uh, we're looking forward to starting production.
‎我们渴望继续工作
Since you've arrived in America,
‎我相信大家在来到美国以后
I believe you've found many things different
‎你们会遇到很多事情
from life in China.
‎发现跟中国不一样
We need to get to know Americans.
‎就是要了解对方
America is a place to let your personality run free.
‎在美国这个地方 就是 ‎似乎就是一个释放的地方
As long as you're not doing anything illegal,
‎你只要是不违法
you're free to follow your heart.
‎你随心所欲
You can even joke about the president.
‎你甚至拿总统开个玩笑
Nobody will do anything to you.
‎都没人会把你怎么样的 是吧
Americans' cars are big and huge, very comfortable.
‎美国人的汽车 宽宽大大的 很舒适
This represents the American sense of casualness.
‎所以这里表现了美国人的这种 这种随意性 ‎只要舒适
They don't place a heavy importance on outfits and attire.
‎穿戴的 打扮并不是那么很要求
If you travel in Europe in the summertime,
‎你们要是到欧洲去旅行的话
and you see someone walking in front of you,
‎有的时候 你走在一个人的后面 ‎你看前面
if he's wearing shorts, vests, and sports shoes,
‎到夏天 大裤衩子 大背心 ‎一双运动鞋
they must be an American.
‎这是 一看到后面 这是美国人
Americans say what they are thinking directly.
‎美国人说话直言不讳
They don't hide anything.
‎他不会是遮遮掩掩的
They are very obvious.
‎表现得非常明显
Everything is practical and realistic.
‎他什么都是务实的
They dislike abstractions and theory in their daily lives.
不搞那些特别抽象的东西 理论的东西 ‎在他的日常生活中
Time is limited today, so I won't keep going.
时间‎因为有限 今天我就不想
The list here is really long.
‎跟大家说更多这种 ‎因为这 很长的一个清单
Wow, thank you.
谢谢
As required by Chairman,
‎我们董事长要求 就是说 安排了
we will have an opening celebration on October 7th.
10月7号 我们这个公司呢 会庆典
From now on,
‎从今天开始
I ask you to keep October 7th in mind
‎请各位 按照10月7号这个目标 我们‎做好我们自己这一块的工作
and work hard towards this grand celebration.
‎来迎接我们这一次盛大的庆典活动
曹董事长
福耀集团创始人兼总裁
Welcome, Chairman. Good to see you.
‎欢迎董事长 见到您很高兴
This one is the Chevrolet S-10.
‎这辆是雪佛兰的S-10
It was made in 1982.
‎1982年 1982年
That's the first one they made.
第一辆车
The first car from the GM plant.
‎而且写的是莫兰的这个工厂
Wow, Dayton was very well developed back then?
‎这个代顿是非常发达的地方
Exactly. A very well developed area.
‎对 这是当年非常发达的 这个代顿
丽贝卡
福耀集团律师
"I have a secret to share, and from the bottom of my heart,
‎"此时此刻 我只想告诉大家的一个 ‎我内心的秘密
I love Ohio, and I love the place
‎就是 我非常地爱俄亥俄
where I invest significantly, here in Dayton."
非常爱我投资的这个所在地 代顿"
This is a historic project that is gonna help grow this community,
‎这是一个历史性的项目 ‎会帮助这个社区成长壮大
give people jobs, and give a future to your kids and my kids
‎为人们提供工作 为你们的孩子 ‎和我的孩子提供未来
that did for those trucks back there when our parents
就像那些卡车一样 就像当年
and grandparents worked on refrigerators and cars.
我们的父母和祖父母生产冰箱和汽车一样
And the future is bright, folks. The future is bright.
‎未来一片光明 父老乡亲们 ‎前途一片光明
Please join me in acknowledging the newly-named Fuyao Avenue.
‎请和我一起确认新命名的福耀大道
"Good morning, everyone. And we meet again today."
‎"尊敬的各位员工 上午好 ‎我们今天在这里又见面了"
Every time I visit this plant, I see a lot of changes.
‎我每一次来这里工厂 都在看到它们在不断的变化
"Every time when I visit, I see great progress."
‎"我每一次来工厂都看到很大的进步"
You see there's still empty space for more equipment.
‎你可以看到很多的位置是要装设备的
It will all be installed within a year.
‎都要在这一年里面完成
"If we can follow through with our plan and become successful here,
‎"我们能够按照我们的计划来成功了以后
this will be a great example
‎美国人能展现出它对外引进外面投资的
of the US successfully attracting foreign investment."
‎一种政策的成功"
Thank you very much.
‎谢谢大家
"Thank you very much."
‎"谢谢大家"
He says that a lot of people lost their jobs in this area,
‎他说这个地方丢了这么多就业机会
and he thanks you for the opportunity.
‎感谢您给我们这个机会
And tell him, one time, he has to come down here
‎告诉他 下次他再过来的时候
and eat some barbecue with us.
‎一定要跟我们一起吃烧烤
-Okay. -Thank you.
‎-好的  ‎-谢谢
So the clients are satisfied?
‎汽车商来看还满意吧
Yes, very satisfied. Especially Chrysler.
‎非常满意 ‎克莱斯勒非常满意
I am pairing an American with a Chinese.
‎而且现在 我给老外搭配一个中国人
The American is the main operator, with a Chinese supervisor by their side.
‎老外掌操作 中国主管站在旁边
They're pretty slow.
‎他们动作比较慢
They have fat fingers.
‎他手指头比较粗
We keep training them over and over.
‎一直教啊一直教
How you doing?
你好吗
The chairman has said from the beginning this is an American company.
‎董事长一开始说过 这是一家美国公司
It's Fuyao Glass America. It needs to be an American company,
‎这是"福耀美国公司" ‎这必须是一家美国公司
we need to treat it like an American company,
‎我们需要把它当成美国公司对待
but we need to be successful just like all our plants throughout the world.
‎但我们需要成功 ‎就像我们在全世界的工厂一样
So, basically, this line, that's the stage.
‎基本上是这条线 那是台子
So from there back to the stage,
‎从那后面就是台子
-and then people out that way. -Facing that way.
‎-人们从那边出来  ‎-面朝那边
-Yeah. -We're talking, like,
‎-嗯  ‎-我们说的就像
a concert stage without cover
‎一个没有顶棚的音乐会舞台
and potentially a overhang for weather.
再另备屋檐预防变天
We're gonna have to plan for that.
‎我们得做好打算
You know what I mean? Like, a concert...
‎是不是 就是上面要有…盖子
Chairman thinks we're okay with October weather,
董事长觉得十月份的天气没问题
So you don't need any hang.
‎所以不需要棚子
-No hang.  - What if it rains?
‎-不需要棚子  ‎-下雨怎么办
It won't.
‎不会下雨
In October, the weather will be like it is today.
‎十月份 天气会和今天差不多的样子
Chairman thinks, in October, the weather will be similar
‎认为十月的天气会类似于
- to... today.  -Today?
‎-今天  ‎-今天
Also, Chairman says that door can't face this way.
‎董事长还说 门不能对着这边
-What door? -Face... You know, the opening right there.
‎-什么门  ‎-面朝… ‎就是那边开着的那个
Well, we just signed a contract, so...
‎我们才签了合同 所以...
-What? -That's a big...
‎-什么  ‎-这个变动很大…
You gotta talk to Jimmy about... I don't know.
‎你得和吉米谈谈...我不知道
- I think it's...  - Jimmy, do you understand what he means?
‎-我觉得是…  ‎-吉米 懂他什么意思吗
We just did a purchase order and ordered a garage door and stuff.
‎我们才下了单 ‎订购了车库门那些东西
So, you gotta face some other direction, I think.
‎我觉得你得面朝其它方向
They already put the door in.
‎他们已经把门安好了
So we're gonna have to change it. Is that okay?
‎那我们要改一下 是这样吗
-Yeah, we need to change it. -Okay.
‎-对 我们需要改  ‎-好的
Yeah, Z, just change it.
‎好的 阿泽 改吧
That's gonna cost us $35,000.
‎大概要花3万5千美金
I have an idea, but I am not sure it's a good one.
‎我有个主意 不知道对不对
We hang two artworks here.
要不要挂两幅
One is something iconic of China,
‎挂一幅中国的 一个代表的
like the Great Wall.
‎比如长城
- The other one is from the US.  - No. Only American ones.
‎-美国的也挂一幅 ‎  -不要 就是挂美国的吧
Only American ones.
‎就是美国的
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
‎入乡随俗
Don't upset them.
‎不要去刺激他们
American, just...
‎美国就…
They haven't done good decorative work here.
‎他这个装修做得很差
This can't be here. It should be moved to the side.
‎不能挂在这里 要挂到旁边去
There are... It's required by law
‎这是法律要求
to have one in here, and it has to be that height.
‎那一定得装一个 而且必须是那个高度
They're just saying
‎我们只是说
- that it should be moved to the side.  - We can move it, yeah.
‎-应该把那个移到另一边  ‎-可以移的
Huh?
怎么了
David says that is the required height.
‎他刚才说这个高度是有要求的
We can't place it down there. It has to be that high.
‎不能放低 一定要放这么高
We can move it to that corner.
‎那我们放这个角
Then up there.
‎放高一点 放这个上面
It's a legal requirement. I'll ask him.
‎是法律要求 我会再问问他
He has to ask and see. He knows this is the right height.
‎他说他要确认一下 ‎他说他知道肯定要这么高
But sometimes, you have to think, uh, before you do,
做之前好好想想 做之前
so then we don't have to redo the work,
‎这样就不用返工
because it costs money.
‎不然又要花钱
Yeah, I've-- That was done...
‎对的 那个就在那…
I wouldn't have necessarily moved, but that was done way before I got here.
‎我不会去动那个 我来之前 那就有了
Catch another big fish!
‎再钓一只大的
Did you all set the bait this way?
‎你们就这样钓钩的吗
- Looks fucking cool! - How do you set it?
‎-这感觉很屌  ‎-怎么钩
You got the Fuyao employees down here doing it.
‎在下面忙活的都是福耀的员工
-Oh, yeah?  - They all work at Fuyao.
‎-是吗  ‎-他们都在福耀上班
-Fuyao or Fiyao?  - Fuyao.
‎-福耀还是飞耀  ‎-福耀
Fiyao? Is that how it's pronounced?
‎飞耀 这样读吗
Fuyao. F-U-Y-A-O.
‎福耀  FUYAO
-Fuyao, Inc.  - Fuyao?
‎-福耀股份有限公司  ‎-福耀
-Yes, Fuyao Company.  - What type of company is that?
‎-是的 福耀公司  ‎-做什么的公司
-Automotive glass. They make the glass...  -Yes, make glass.
‎-汽车玻璃 他们是做玻璃的…  ‎-对 做玻璃的
-Oh, nice. Okay. -The car glass.
‎-挺好的  ‎-汽车玻璃
-Okay, wow, glass.  - Yes.
‎-玻璃  ‎-是的
-Ooh, that's a big one right there. -Big, yes.
‎-是条大鱼  ‎-大鱼 对
Very big.
很大
-How speak English?  - Carp.
‎-用英语怎么说  ‎-Carp
- Carp.  - Carp.
‎-鲤鱼  ‎-是鲤鱼
C-A-R-P. Carp.
‎C-A-R-P 鲤鱼
- C-A-R-P. Carp. Carp. - Yep. Those are carp.
‎-C-A-R-P 鲤鱼  -‎这些是鲤鱼
Now, the carp that you're catching
‎你们钓的那种鲤鱼
likes corn and Wheaties.
‎喜欢吃玉米和麦地麦片
Have you heard of Wheaties cereal?
‎听说过麦地牌麦片吗
- I don't know. Wheaty...  - Never heard of Wheaties?
‎-不知道 麦…  ‎-从没听说过麦地牌
-Wheaties? I don't know. -Wheaties.
‎-麦地牌 不知道  ‎-麦地牌
-Wheaties. -Wheaties.
‎-麦地牌  ‎-麦地牌
Yeah, buddy. You'd be surprised how good Wheaties works.
对 兄弟 用麦地牌的鱼饵 你会大有收获
Wheaties? W-E-D-S?
‎麦地牌 W-E-D-S
‎W-E-E-T-E-S
W-E-E-T-E-S.
- No. I don't know that. - Okay. Yup, it does the best.
‎-不 我不知道  ‎-好的 那是最好的钓饵
Looks like they're getting ready to go, huh?
‎看来他们准备走了
We're going home to gut the fish, and we'll come back.
‎要回家杀鱼去内脏 马上过来
All right, Leon. I'mma go home and get me something to eat.
‎好了 里昂 我要回家吃东西了
- I'll be back down.  - Okay, okay.
‎-待会再来  ‎-好的
- I'll be back down. - Nice to meet you.
‎-待会再来  -见到你很高兴  ‎
All right, Leon.
好的 里昂
- Patty? - Yes?
‎-帕蒂  ‎-怎么了
-I'm getting ready to leave. -Okay.
‎-我准备走了 ‎ -好的
-All right. -Have a good day.
‎-好的  ‎-祝你今天顺利
For a year and a half, I didn't have anything.
‎整整一年半  我没有任何收入来源
When I started at Fuyao,
在福耀上班后
I was thankful, I was blessed, I was...
‎我很感激 很幸福 我…
just on my knees, thanking God that I had something.
跪下感谢上帝 我终于有事做了
- Hey, what's up, man?  - Hey, what's going on?
‎-嘿 兄弟 怎么样  ‎-嘿 你怎么样
Going good.
‎挺好的
-All right? -Yeah.
‎-都好吗  ‎-对
This is the best game in town right now.
‎这是现在最理想的选择
Going back in there for the first time,
‎第一次回到那
I kind of welled up because...
‎我有点热泪盈眶 因为…
I could see the post locations...
‎我可以看到标注的位置…
you know, on the columns, you know?
柱子上的标注
Which actually tells you where you are in the plant.
‎会告诉你在厂里的什么位置
People still get lost. I said, "I don't get lost."
‎人们还是会迷路 我说 "我不会迷路"
At General Motors, I was making $29
在通用的时候 我每小时赚29
肖妮
玻璃检查员
and some change an hour.
‎另外还有一些收入
At Fuyao, I make 12.84.
‎在福耀 我每小时赚12.84
Back then, if my kids wanted a pair of new gym shoes,
‎以前 我的孩子们要是想买 ‎一双新运动鞋
I could just go get them. I can't just do that now.
‎我就直接买了 现在没法这样了
We lost our home, we lost a vehicle.
‎我们没了房 也没了车
- Have a good weekend. -All right, you too.
‎-提前祝你周末愉快  ‎-好的 你也是
When GM closed, I foreclosed on my house.
‎通用关闭的时候 ‎我屋子的抵押赎回权被取消
Ever since then,
‎从那以后
I have struggled to try to get back to middle class again.
‎我挣扎着想再次回到中产阶级
吉尔
叉车操作员
I've been living in my sister's basement.
‎我一直住在我姐姐的地下室里
I am fortunate enough to have a bedroom.
还好 我还有间卧室
And the only thing in here is my end tables and my TV.
‎这里只有床头柜和电视是我的
The bed isn't mine. The bed is theirs.
‎床不是我的 是他们的
You know? So, yeah.
‎你懂的 所以
We've been down about... I don't know, 45 minutes or so.
‎我们已经停机… ‎不知道 45分钟了吧
Water spots, I guess.
‎我猜是水渍
Thank you.
谢谢
They've drained the washer. They're slowing it down.
‎他们把清洗机的水抽光了 ‎速度就慢下来了
They get upset when we're all trying to figure something out.
‎我们想找到原因的时候 他们就会烦
Everybody gets upset, and then everybody's upset
‎大家就会很烦 每个人都很烦
in their own language,
开始各说各的语言
and then everybody just walks their own way, and...
‎然后各自离开 然后...
meet back here in five minutes.
五分钟之后再过来
Set the water temperature to 60°.
‎首先水温调到60度
Because it has high alkalinity.
‎因为这个是强碱性
Okay. Later on, we're going to try to lower the...
‎好的 之后我们要把这个降低…
驳回
Okay.
‎好了
王
窑炉工程师
Be careful!
‎当心
Beautiful! Beautiful!
‎很好 很好
Down a little.
‎下来一点
Down a little bit!
‎下来一点点
-Allen wrench. - Allen. Allen.
‎-艾伦扳手 -艾伦 艾伦
Allen wrench.
艾伦扳手
-Allen wrench. - Allen wrench.
‎-艾伦扳手  ‎-艾伦扳手
My first impression of Ohio was how flat it is.
‎到俄亥俄的最初印象是 比较平原化
My family's in China.
‎我的国内 国内的家人
Two lovely children
‎我目前 小孩子 也有自己的两个比较可爱的小孩
and a beautiful wife.
‎还有一个漂亮的老婆
Fuyao offered me my first job at 18.
‎我从18岁成年之后 第一个跨入的行业就是福耀
I've worked in the furnace for more than 20 years.
‎我到目前为止 能在这个岗位坚持了20年
It's a hard job, but I love it.
‎就是因为喜欢这个工作 ‎喜欢这个岗位
Because of the language barrier and cultural differences,
‎有时候 毕竟还有个语言交流方面 还有文化
it's hard to quickly integrate everyone's ideas.
‎就是说一时半刻很难把每个人的想法 ‎都能很好地融合在一起
I don't have much time to eat every day.
‎我每天经常没有时间吃饭
So every week, I bring a box of Twinkies.
‎每个礼拜都要带一包
This is my lunch.
‎这个就当饭
I eat two at a time.
‎一次吃两块
Look at the red sticks. This one is broken.
‎我们这个 红红的 这个就是断掉了
We have to pull it out by ourselves.
‎我们就要人在这边把这拿出来
Look at the scars on my arm.
‎所以说我手上的伤
These are all scalds.
‎到处都是这个
I got burned.
‎全部都是被烫伤的 烫到了
Air.
‎空气
Uh, Wong and I have spent a lot of time together
‎王和我 我们俩在一起相处了很长时间
with him teaching me everything...
‎他什么都会教我…
Mother's Day, we spent the whole weekend working together
‎母亲节 我们整个周末都在加班
with our little translators, talking back and forth.
‎我们的翻译人员也在 ‎来来回回地翻译
罗伯
窑炉主管
That's when they told me that they had to be here two years,
‎他们那个时候告诉我说 ‎他们要在这待两年
away from their family, no extra pay.
‎远离家人 没有额外补贴
That really made me start thinking
我开始真正地思考
and appreciating what they're doing for us more and more.
也‎越来越感谢他们为我们所做的一切
I've ate at their house, they've ate at my home.
‎我在他们家吃过饭 ‎他们也来我家吃饭
We've just bonded.
‎我们之间有了感情纽带
And we've tried to learn each other's culture.
‎我们试着了解彼此的文化
I got the big idea, Thanksgiving, to...
‎我有个好主意 感恩节…
invite my close friends,
‎邀请我最好的朋友
which should have been about four or five of them.
‎应该是四 五个人
It ended up being, I think, 13.
‎最后来了…我想 13个
Bought a 25-pound turkey, the biggest honey-baked ham I could get,
‎买了一只11公斤的火鸡 ‎买了我能买到的最大的蜜汁火腿
and all of the traditional trimmings.
‎还有所有传统的佐料
I know that in China they're not allowed to have guns.
‎我知道他们在中国拿不到枪
We had my 12-gauge shotgun out there, pistols.
‎我有把12毫米口径的猎枪 还有手枪
Couple of the very brave ones wanted to go up and down the road with me
‎几个胆子比较大的人 还想跟我‎骑着哈雷摩托
on my Harley.
去兜兜风
They talked about it forever.
他们一直把这件事挂在嘴边
That made me happy.
我很开心
That's the front page of The Washington Post, fellas.
这是"华盛顿邮报"的头版 ‎诸位
That's big-time.
‎很成功
一位中国亿万富豪将全部家当以及数万‎美国人的工作机会孤注一掷于俄州工厂
is that, out of our 2,000 people,
‎就是在我们两千人中
they picked the number one UAW...
‎他们采访了汽车工会的...
uh, organizer and sympathizer to talk to.
‎头号组织者和支持者
Number one.
‎头号人物
- Anyway, um, it's a big deal. - That's a big deal.
‎-总之 这是件大事  ‎-是件大事
With all of this scrutiny
所有这些审查
and with all of this visibility comes even more responsibility on us
‎所有这些报道出来了 我们就更有责任
to do things right.
‎妥善行事
Now the whole world is watching.
‎现在全世界都在观察我们
Now the whole world is watching us.
‎现在整个世界都在观察我们
It should say have "to be the world."
‎应该在"领先世界"里面加个the
朝着成为领先世界 ‎汽车玻璃提供者前进
Yeah, they said they had an S.
‎他们说有个S[所有格]
福耀美国
Good afternoon.
‎下午好
-Right? -Good afternoon!
‎-对吧  ‎-下午好
Good afternoon.
‎下午好
Thank you guys very much.
‎非常感谢大家
You don't know how important this is to Fuyao
‎你们不知道这对福耀 ‎以及对董事长来说
and to the chairman.
有多重要
The plant looks great.
‎工厂看上去非常棒
These people are coming here
‎人们来到这
学好玻璃 造好玻璃 输好玻璃
to see something that they never in their lifetime thought would happen.
‎看到了他们这辈子都没想到会发生的事情
You have given hope and you have given life to a community
‎你们给这个曾经荒凉的地方带来了希望
that was desolate.
带来了活力
This is one of the greatest projects in the history of the United States.
‎这是美国史上最伟大的项目之一
So, be proud, and most importantly,
‎所以请感到自豪 最重要的是
have fun.
‎要开心
Two lands,
‎两片土地
-the bridge is what brings us together. -Yeah.
‎-桥梁把我们连接起来  ‎-对
And the niukou. How do you say in English?
‎对 纽扣 用英语怎么讲
-The bond. -Bond. Yeah, bond. Bond.
‎-连结  ‎-连结 对 连结
Yes, bond.
‎是的 连结
Welcome.
‎欢迎
Welcome to the US!
‎欢迎来到美国
Today the chairman's vision has been fulfilled.
‎今天 董事长的愿景得以实现
Fuyao has invested close to 500 million.
‎福耀投资将近五亿美金
Ni hao.
‎你好
Really good seeing you guys. Thank you.
‎真的很开心见到你们 谢谢
Thanks for having us out here. We really appreciate it.
‎感谢邀请我们过来 非常感激
-It's a big deal. -Absolutely.
‎-这是大事  ‎-绝对的
This is big. A lot of people.
‎很盛大 很多人
-Nice weather, man. -Oh, my gosh.
‎-天气很好 伙计  ‎-我的天
Chairman ordered the weather.
‎董事长安排了天气
-Oh, I mean, it couldn't be better. -Right.
‎-简直不能再完美了  ‎-对
Hang in there.
‎坚持住
-How you doing, Dave? -Good to see you.
‎-戴维 你还好吗  ‎-见到你真好
"My dear guests and friends, good morning."
‎"尊敬的嘉宾和朋友们 上午好"
"Today, we hold the opening ceremony
‎"福耀集团美国代顿项目竣工庆典
of Fuyao Glass America."
‎今天在这里隆重举行"
We've heard both candidates for president
‎我们听说两位总统候选人 ‎
refer to Ohio as the Rust Belt.
把俄亥俄称为铁锈带
And, you know, you look at... look at this today,
‎看看今天的这番景象
and we reject that term.
‎我们拒绝那个词
With Chairman Cao, we know how to make everything in this state.
‎有了曹董事长  我们知道 ‎如何利用这个州的资源
And, uh, this is a terrific example.
‎这就是很出色的范例
One last point: I know many workers here are trying to form a union
‎最后一点 我知道这里很多工人 ‎打算组成工会
to strengthen their voice in this great company.
以便‎在这家伟大的公司 努力表达自己的声音
Ohio has a rich... a rich, rich history
‎俄亥俄州有着丰富的
of unions and management working together.
‎工会和管理层携手合作的历史
I support those in this community, in this plant, in this crowd
‎我支持那些在这个社区 这家工厂 这群人中的那些人
that want to vote on whether or not to join a union.
‎无论他们是否加入工会
I hope Fuyao looks at it the same way. Thank you all so much.
‎我希望福耀看法也是如此 ‎非常感谢大家
Who the fuck does he think he is?
‎他把自己当什么人了
Out of place, totally out of place.
‎不称职 太不称职了
Fuck him.
‎去他妈的
Three, two, one!
‎三 二 一
Our glass is totally made in USA.
‎我们的玻璃是纯美国制造
Ladies, you're doing a beautiful job.
‎女士们 你们做得非常好
Create good glass and transfer good glass.
‎造好玻璃 输好玻璃
The senator mentioned the workers union in his speech.
‎议员在讲话中提到工会问题
Does Fuyao have any good strategies for avoiding these risks?
‎不知道福耀在这方面有什么好计策 ‎或者会有什么措施去预防这方面的风险
Hey, Charles. How you doing, man?
‎查尔斯 怎么样 伙计
Dave, there's one thing I gotta talk to you about.
‎戴维 我有件事得跟你说
Regarding Sherrod Brown's comments...
‎关于谢罗德·布朗的讲话...
Yes.
对
You know, that's obviously not beneficial to us.
‎那显然对我们不利
Absolutely right.
‎完全正确
-Don't wanna talk about certain topics. -Correct.
‎-我们不想谈论这类话题  ‎-对
So I think, at this point, Chairman, you know,
‎我觉得这个关头 你知道的 董事长
will definitely ask about
‎肯定会问
- what we're gonna do about it.  - It's okay. Yeah. Yeah.
‎-我们准备怎么做  ‎-好的 好的
I'm gonna have to kill a senator.
‎我想杀了那个参议员
I'm gonna take those big scissors and cut the... Senator Brown's head.
‎我要拿把大剪刀… ‎把布朗参议员的脑袋剪下来
He...
‎他…
-It's big. -He didn't tell us he was gonna do that.
‎-有想法  ‎-他没告诉我们会搞这么一出
He did that on purpose, so they're cut off.
‎他是故意的 不会让他们来了
They'll never be allowed in the plant again.
‎再也不会让他来工厂了
You all know our stand on this.
‎从战略上 首先你已经知道了 ‎我们集团的意见
We don't want to see the union developing here.
‎我们跟你一样的 就不愿意看到它在这里发展
"First, you all know our stand on this,
"‎首先 你们都知道我们对此的立场
that we want to avoid unions."
‎我们希望避免工会"
If we have a union, it will impact our efficiency,
‎因为工会在这里 ‎会影响我们的劳动效率
thus hurting our company.
‎直接影响到我们的企业效益
It will create loss for us.
‎那这个会造成损失
If a union comes in, I'm shutting down.
‎我已经很明确的态度 工会进来 ‎我关门不做了
They keep interfering with my production.
‎那么他现在这样做的话 ‎我生产线开不起来的
Slowly bleeding money is even worse than a union.
‎那个慢亏比工会破坏更厉害
"Uh, right now,
‎"现在
if they're creating extreme inefficiency in my production,
如果他们给我的生产 ‎造成极端低效
I'm just bleeding money."
‎我就是大量地亏钱"
John, if you want to continue to be president,
‎约翰 我和你说 ‎你如果想在这里当总经理
you have to listen to my advice.
‎一定要听我的劝告
Every piece of glass counts.
‎每一片玻璃都十分重要
Every piece that goes down that line and goes... gets on that customer truck,
‎生产线出来的每一片玻璃 ‎都会送到顾客车上
it matters.
‎每一片都很重要
Our customers are counting on us.
‎客户都指望着我们
General Motors, Chrysler, Toyota, Honda.
‎通用汽车 克莱斯勒 ‎丰田 本田
Whether it's coming from China or whether it's coming from Dayton,
‎无论玻璃是中国产的 还是代顿产的
it's the same... it's the same thing.
‎都是一样的...一样的玻璃
We have to be able to provide them glass
‎我们必须给他们提供
at the same level of efficiency,
‎同等效率的玻璃
the same level of cost and quality.
‎同等的成本和品质
It's audit day.
大家今天审核
We don't have glass to show them.
‎我们没玻璃给人家
We should have some ready
‎起码要给人家一小部分 他拿去运转
for the customers to check.
‎让客户今天和明天来看
The glass is gonna run through the furnace,
‎窑炉出来的玻璃
basically the same as the other furnace over here.
‎基本上和这里其它窑炉出来的 ‎是一样的
This one's just a little bit faster.
‎这个只是会快一点
So it comes down the line, it comes in here.
‎从流水线上下来 再到这里
Down in here is another one of those free-liners
‎下面是另一位流水线员工
that puts the glass into position.
‎把玻璃放在合适的位置
This is an automatic...
‎这是自动…
Keep it or throw it out?
‎留着还是扔掉
- Throw out.  - Throw it? Okay.
‎-扔了吧  ‎-扔了吗 好吧
There must be some flaws if the glass exploded.
它炸玻璃 必炸 这是什么现象什么现象
The overall quality of the glass is not good enough,
‎玻璃的质量 我也看了一下 玻璃的整个质量 还是那个
but there's no way to improve it now. We still want to achieve our targets.
‎但现在没办法 现在我们还是要冲量
One is output. The second is rate of finished products.
‎一 冲量  二 冲成品率
We need one more person.
‎还需要更多人
Transfer someone from China here.
‎从中国调过来人
You have the Chinese, who want numbers on this side.
‎这边的中国人要考虑追求数量
You have Quality, who wants customer satisfaction on this side.
‎这一边要考虑品质 来提高客户满意度
And we're in the middle.
‎我们夹在中间
Today was a shitshow, totally a shitshow.
‎今天出丑了 出大丑了
Any little microscopic chip can cause a breakage.
‎任何微小的碎屑都会引起炸裂
As soon as it hits the press, it begins to cool.
‎碰到冲压机 就会冷却
If there's a...
‎如果有…
Got it?
你可以吗
Four hundred-and-something degrees.
‎四百多华氏度
And they're six feet away from it?
中间才隔了一米八
We need to find some solutions,
‎我们得找到解决办法
约翰
福耀安全部主管
whether it's them stepping into a colder room
‎不管是他们一离开那
as soon as they leave there...
‎就进入更凉的屋子…
We've gotta get them some relief.
‎我们得帮他们找到解决办法
How much time do you spend in there?
‎你要在这待多久
About ten minutes or so.
大概十分钟
Ten minutes an hour, a day, a...?
每小时待10分钟 还是每天...
Sometimes every hour.
‎有时候是每小时待10分钟
So every hour? So you go in there, it's about 200 degrees,
‎每小时 所以你进去里面 大概200度…
and you clean up in there for about two hours. All right.
‎然后在那收拾两小时 好吧
The conditions...
‎工作条件…
are not favorable.
‎不太好
Doing the same thing over and over again.
‎不断重复着相同的事情
That wears on you.
‎会让你精疲力尽
Body, mind...
‎身心疲惫…
You're so... It's...
‎你会非常…
Sometimes you think...
‎有时候你会想…
"Why am I doing this?"
‎"我为什么要做这个"
You think about whether you have the stamina
‎你会思考 自己有没有毅力
and the will to do this type of job.
是不是想来做这种工作
Anything they're not happy about?
‎有没有意见
It gets really hot in here.
‎里面非常热
Our American colleagues are very afraid of heat.
‎我们的美国同事非常怕热
We try to give them the environment they want,
‎我尽量保证能达到他们[想要]的环境
as long as it's within a reasonable budget.
‎在我们合理的成本之下
The spaces between the production lines are pretty narrow.
‎我们的生产线 老板 都是每条线每条线 这样[排得]很紧
The Occupational Safety & Health Administration (OSHA)
‎美国职业安全与健康管理局 OSHA
thinks it's too dense.
他认为我们太紧
"A tall tree catches the wind."
‎"这个叫树大招风"
Yes, it's a huge tree.
‎对 太大了
Let's welcome Chairman!
‎欢迎董事长
Dear staff,
‎尊敬的各位员工
good morning.
‎上午好
We haven't reached our goals.
‎这个现在 这个经济指标没有达标
This is a very tough challenge for us.
‎这是一个非常艰巨的任务
We are all Chinese.
‎我们都是中国人
We were born
我们自从 出生那一天开始
of Chinese mothers.
在中国人的母亲下面 生出来的话呢
No matter where you die or are buried, you will always be Chinese.
‎我们到死 不论被埋在什么地方 ‎都是中国人
The motherland is like a mother.
‎祖国是我们的母亲
This is eternal.
‎这是永恒的
Today, Chinese come to the US to operate factories.
‎你今天 中国人到我这里来办企业
The most important thing is not how much money we earn,
‎我们最最关键的第一件事情不是赚多少钱的问题
but how this will change Americans' views of the Chinese
‎为的是让美国人改变对中国人的看法
and towards China.
‎对中国的看法
Every Chinese person should do things for our country and our people.
‎因此每一个中国人 ‎都应该树立这种观念 就是报国为民
It's down to every one of you here.
‎关键靠我们在座的这些人
American workers are not efficient and output is low.
‎美国工人效率低 产出低
I can't manage them.
‎不能管的
When we try to manage them, they threaten to get help from the union.
‎一管 他说 我要找工会去了
How can we make Americans understand
‎怎么能让美国人理解
that the Chinese can open factories in America?
‎并接受我们中国人在那边投资
This is a big problem.
‎这是比较大的问题
福建省福清市
- Hey. Welcome. Thank you.  - Welcome. Nice to see you again.
‎-欢迎 谢谢  ‎-欢迎 很高兴再次见到你们
- How are you? Good?  - Good.
‎-还好吗 挺好的  ‎-挺好
-How are you? -Hi. Welcome.
‎-你好吗  ‎-欢迎
♪ Noble sentiments ♪
♪‎ 高尚的情操 ♪
‎♪ Are transparent ♪
♪ 一片透明 ♪
♪ For the sake of transparency ♪
‎♪ 为了一片透明 ♪
‎♪ We've gone through difficulties ♪
♪ 我们历尽艰辛 ♪
‎♪ For the sake of transparency ♪
♪ 为了一片透明 ♪
‎♪ We've struggled every bit ♪
♪ 我们奋力拼搏 ♪
‎♪ Fuyao holds up ♪
♪ 福耀托起 ♪
‎♪ A transparent world ♪
♪ 透明的世界 ♪
♪ China is filled with spring ♪
‎♪ 春满中华 ♪
‎♪ And happiness is everywhere ♪
♪ 福耀人间 ♪
‎♪ All the blessings from Fuyao ♪
♪ 福耀的祝福 ♪
‎♪ Are transparent ♪
♪ 每一片都是透明 ♪
Ni hao.
你好
- Ni hao. - Pleasure.
‎-你好  ‎-幸会
Ni hao. Good morning. Pleasure to meet you.
‎你好 早上好 幸会
- Good morning. - Good morning.
‎-早上好  ‎-欢迎
-Ni hao. -Nice to meet you.
‎-你好  ‎-幸会
-Thank you. -Good morning.
‎-谢谢  ‎-早上好
Nice to meet you.
‎幸会
-Ni hao. -Ni hao.
‎-你好  ‎-你好
Ni hao.
‎你好
Good morning, my name is John Withrow. I'm supervisor in Lamination.
‎早上好 我是约翰·维斯罗 ‎压层部主管
Good morning. I'm Austin Cole.
‎早上好 我是阿斯汀·科尔
I'm a temporary backlight production supervisor.
‎我是背光生产部临时主管
Jon Helton, the continuous improvement supervisor.
‎我是乔恩·赫尔顿 持续改进部主管
Good morning, Darren Noble. Lead supervisor, ARG packaging assembly.
‎早上好 我是戴伦·诺博 ‎售后更换玻璃包装组装主管
Welcome, everybody.
‎欢迎大家
Welcome home.
‎欢迎回家
The whole world is looking at FGA and you guys are the top guns.
整个世界都在关注着福耀美国 你们都是顶梁柱
We are investing in the US.
‎我们在美国投资
We love the country, and we want to be part of the country
‎我们爱美国 ‎希望成为美国的一部分
and provide benefits to the country.
‎为美国带去好处
And we hope that FGA will be profitable soon
‎我们希望福耀美国能尽快盈利
and to let our customers know that we are a strong company.
‎让客户知道我们公司很强大
This is a very valuable time and also a special time.
现在这个时期很宝贵  也很特殊
Tonight we'll have you join our year-end group party,
‎今晚我们会让诸位参加集团年会
and, uh, we also hope you can, uh, get some time to taste local cuisines.
‎还希望诸位能有时间尝尝我们当地美食
Thank you for putting us up in a nice hotel.
‎感谢为我们提供这么好的酒店
Yes.
‎对
I think that we are also anxious to see how your process runs
‎我觉得我们也很想参观学习你们的运营流程
and look forward to taking back new ideas
希望能带回一些新思想
and implementations to help us run better as well.
‎和实施方法 帮助我们更好地运行
I can't breathe in that.
扣上的话 我就喘不上气了
欢迎福耀美国参观福耀集团
Nonstop.
马不停蹄
- Okay. - Okay.
‎-好的  -好的
This is the line they'll run 7,000 on?
‎这条流水线每天走七千片吗
We hope someday to get this good.
‎我们希望也能生产这么多
Attention!
‎立正
Dress right!
‎向右看齐
Keep an eye on the distance
‎前后左右距离
between yourself and others.
‎看好自己的前后面
Eyes front!
‎向前看
Straddle.
‎稍息
Hello, everyone!
‎大家好
Good! We are good.
‎好 很好 可以更好
Number off!
‎报数
-One. -Two.‎
-1  ‎-2
-Three. -Four.
‎-3  ‎-4
‎-Five. -Six.
-5  ‎-6
‎-Seven. -Eight.
-7  ‎-8
‎-Nine. -Ten.
-9  ‎-10
‎Eleven.
-Twelve. -Thirteen.
‎-12  ‎-13
-Fourteen. -Fifteen.
‎-14  ‎-15
-Sixteen. -Seventeen.
‎-16  ‎-17
‎Eighteen.
Nineteen. Report!
‎19 报告
There should be 19 people in this team, and all 19 people are here.
‎本班应到19人 实到19人
Over!
‎报告完毕
Good afternoon.
‎大家下午好
‎下午好 ‎下午好
- Sorry. - Sorry! Sorry!
‎-对不起  ‎-对不起 对不起
- Please. - Please. Please.
‎-请  ‎-请 请
- Thank you. - Thank you. Thank you.
‎-谢谢  ‎-谢谢 谢谢
Attention.
‎立正
-Our team name is? - Improvement!
‎-我们的队名  ‎-改进队
Our slogan is?
‎我们的口号
To stand still is to move back!
‎逆水行舟 不进则退
Attention!
‎立正
The preparation meeting is over.
‎我们今天的班前会到此结束
Dismissed.
‎散会
I heard things are not going too well over there.
‎听说你们那边做得很不顺利
Right. That's true. That's why we're doing training here.
‎对 是的 所以我们来这边培训
You guys have eight days off every month.
‎再讲句实在话 你一个月放八天的假
You have all the weekends.
‎周末都有假
Only eight hours a day. That's an easy life.
‎一天八个小时 这已经很爽了
Yes.
‎对
These workers only have one or two days off per month.
‎我们中国人 一个月 [休息]大概一到两天
They're not too happy about that.
‎他们都有点不干
That's why I told you American workers are too lazy.
‎所以我跟你说 美国员工就是太懒了
It's just your nature. But you're not bad.
‎是你们本性就是这样 不是说烂
-Every person can be changed. -We have some extremely diligent workers.
‎-人都可以改变的  ‎-我们有一些很努力的
Very motivated, very ambitious.
‎想进步的 想上去的那些人
They're great.
‎非常好
But most workers are there just to make money,
‎然后大部分是 我来了是为了收工资
not to make glass.
‎不是为了做玻璃
How many hours a day do they work?
‎一个班上几个小时
Eight hours per shift.
‎他们是一个班八个小时
Eight hours. So about 100 dollars a day.
‎八小时 算一百美金吧
Here we say you have to be worthy of your salary.
‎在我们中国有句古话说 ‎你拿多少钱做多少事
You need to prove you deserve it. You understand, right?
‎要对得起这份钱嘛 你应该明白吧
Yes, I understand.
‎明白啦
I heard that your workers like to joke around and talk a lot.
‎我 反正我是听别人说 你们那边工人 ‎嘻嘻哈哈开玩笑说话聊天
The best tool we can use is duct tape.
‎我们最好的工具就是那个 胶带
Put it over their mouths. They will perform better.
‎把胶带封在嘴巴上 他们会表现更好
-Tape? -Tape on their mouths.
‎-口袋  ‎-胶带放在口上 就是贴在口上的胶带
Can you do that there?
‎你们能贴吗
No, we can't. But if we could do that, we'd have improved production.
‎不能 我是说 可是如果我们这样贴 ‎我们产量会上来
Because they're too chatty now.
‎因为他们现在都啰嗦
Well, the most important thing
‎最重要的一点
is that you all should be united and concentrate your efforts.
‎你要让他们形成一种团结力
It's not bad working here.
‎工作还可以吧
I'm married.
‎有成家
My child is in my hometown.
‎孩子也在老家
We don't have many holidays, so I don't have much time to go back home.
‎有时候不放假 不让回去 也很少回去
Only during the Spring Festival, once a year.
‎基本上等到过年的时候才能回去
We work 12 hours a shift.
‎我们上12个小时
I'm tired, but I have no choice.
‎累啊 累也没办法啊
We work whenever we're asked by our leader.
‎领导叫我们做我们就做
I have two kids now.
‎我现在有两个小孩
One is six months old, the other is four years old.
‎一个才半岁 一个才四岁
They're pretty young.
‎孩子比较小一点
If we're too busy, we may not be able to take days off.
‎看玻璃的情况了 如果做玻璃比较忙的话 ‎那就有可能休不了
I only go home once or twice a year.
‎反正一年回去一次 两次
My older kid is 11, and the younger one is eight.
‎大的有十一周岁了 小的八周岁
I work long hours and I spend very little time with them.
‎就是加班 陪他们的时间特别少
Holy shit.
‎我的天
They don't have any safety glasses on, nothing. Unbelievable.
‎他们没戴安全防护镜 什么都没有 ‎难以置信
Those aren't even cut-resistant gloves.
‎这都不是防割手套
Man, that is nuts.
老天 简直疯了
You gotta be kidding me.
‎这是在逗我吧
The glass in our factory...
‎我们厂里的玻璃…
Different glass colors have different values for recycling.
不同颜色的玻璃 价值不一样
So they have to sort the colors.
他们要分类
These people sit there all day long doing that.
‎这些人整天坐在那捡玻璃
That's fucking crazy. Picking through fucking glass like that.
疯了吧 捡玻璃也不做什么防护措施
福耀工会和党委总部
We are energetic at Fuyao.
‎我们在福耀也是很有激情的
All of us are energetic and happy to work here.
‎就是说整个都挺有激情的 ‎我们在这做也很开心
All of our workers are members of the workers union.
‎一样的 所有的都是 都是工会成员
何世猛
福耀工会主席
福耀党委第一书记
曹德旺董事长的妹夫
Mao Zedong,
‎毛泽东
and this is Deng Xiaoping,
‎这个邓小平
Jiang Zemin,
‎江泽民
Hu Jintao,
‎胡锦涛
Xi Jinping.
‎习近平
These are the five leaders since China was established.
‎我们建国到现在五任领导人
Without backing from the government, the company wouldn't get too far.
‎没有政府的大力支持 ‎企业肯定走不好
Our workers union and the company
‎工会跟企业
are closely related to each other.
‎是密切联系在一起
They are like two gears rotating together.
‎是跟齿轮一样转动
We need our workers to fight for Fuyao's success.
都把他拉入 都为福耀来[奋斗]
We are all in the same boat.
‎因为我们是在这艘船上
Keeping the boat safe means everyone is safe.
‎船好 大家才会好
If the boat sinks, everyone loses their jobs.
‎船开翻了 大家连饭碗都没了
It's quite simple.
‎这也很简单的道理
Chairman Cao, here is a hada for you.
曹总 给您献个哈达
Next on the red carpet will be workers from two teams.
‎那么接下来 即将向红毯走来的是两个班组
They have won the Excellent Team award.
‎他们就是今天晚上获得优秀班组奖的 ‎两个班组的代表
Year 2017...
‎2017年…
"Soaring ambitions."
‎"心怀志远"
"The spirit of craftsmanship is all over China."
‎"工匠精神 在华夏弘扬"
Let's welcome Chairman Cao with our warmest applause!
‎让我们以最热烈的掌声 ‎欢迎曹董事长入场
Dear Chairman,
‎尊敬的董事长
dear colleagues,
‎我们亲爱的福耀家人们
tonight is a gathering time for our Fuyao family.
‎今晚是我们福耀大家庭的 一个团聚的日子
Everybody performing tonight works here at Fuyao.
‎今天晚上所有的演员都是福耀的员工
♪ We've cooked A joyful New Year's Eve dinner ♪
‎♪ 把快乐做成年夜饭 才格外的香甜 ♪
♪ The family is cheerful The family is joyful ♪
‎♪  一家子情融融 一家人心相连 ♪
♪ We wish you radiant joy ♪
‎♪ 祝福你们喜气洋洋日子红艳艳 ♪
♪ Happy New Year We wish you an auspicious New Year ♪
‎♪  快乐新年呀 快乐吉祥年 ♪
♪ We wish you a safe year We wish your family a fortunate New Year ♪
‎♪  一年四季岁岁平安家家都团圆 ♪
♪ May you be happy and prosperous! ♪
‎♪ 恭喜你发财 ♪
♪ May the best come, may the worst leave ♪
‎♪ 好的请过来 不好的请走开 ♪
♪ Always be courteous and polite ♪
‎♪ 礼多人不怪 ♪
♪ May you be happy and prosperous! ♪
‎♪ 恭喜发财 ♪
Come on! Two words have become really popular recently.
‎大家快来呀 最近有俩词特别流行
What are the words?
‎什么词 ‎什么词
Intelligence. Lean.
‎智能 精益
‎♪ Intelligent and lean manufacturing ♪
♪ 智能精益是趋势 ♪
♪ All industries should adopt them ♪
‎♪ 各行都得往上靠 ♪
♪ Finance, service, manufacturing ♪
‎♪ 金融 服务 制造业 ♪
♪ Intelligent and lean manufacturing ♪
‎♪ 智能精益少不了 ♪
♪ Technology is developing rapidly ♪
‎♪ 科技高速在发展 ♪
♪ The information age Has already arrived... ♪
♪ ‎信息时代已来到... ♪
♪ Employee relations system is amazing ♪
‎♪ ER这系统不得了 ♪
♪ Great at resource integration And market response ♪
‎♪ 整合资源响应市场 ♪
♪ Waste eliminated And revenues generated ♪
‎♪ 消除浪费增收益 ♪
♪ Transition, upgrade Promotion, integration ♪
‎♪ 转型升级要推广 变化融合来开创 ♪
♪ A corporation with lean manufacturing ♪
‎♪ 精益企业能聚魄 ♪
♪ Fuyao is creating a new future! ♪
‎♪ 福耀使命创未来 ♪
Uh, we're very impressed,
‎印象非常深刻
everybody from the United States, with China's operations.
‎所有美国来的同事对中国的业务操作‎印象非常深刻
Very harmonious people.
‎大家非常友好
You see it and you feel it.
‎看得到也感觉得到
♪ Young man There's no need to feel down ♪
♪ 年轻人 不必沮丧 ♪
♪ I said, young man Pick yourself off the ground ♪
♪ 我说 年轻人 站起来吧 ♪
♪ I said, young man 'Cause you're in a new town ♪
♪ 我说 年轻人 因为你来到了新环境 ♪
♪ There's no need to be unhappy ♪
♪ 要开开心心的 ♪
♪ It's fun to stay at the YMCA ♪
♪ 待在基督教青年会很快乐 ♪
♪ They have everything For the men to enjoy ♪
♪ 这应有尽有 请尽情享乐♪
♪ You can hang out with all the boys ♪
♪ 可以和所有男孩在一起 ♪
♪ It's fun to stay at the YMCA... ♪
♪ 待在基督教青年会很快乐... ♪
Please hold the hand of your bride.
‎请拉起新娘的手
From this moment on,
从这一刻起
no matter poor or rich,
‎无论贫穷和富贵
you will always care for her,
‎你都将 关心她 呵护她
cherish her, and protect her,
‎珍惜她 保护她
until forever.
‎到永远
Will you?
‎你愿意吗
- Yes, I will. - Yes, I will.
‎-我愿意  ‎-我愿意
We're one...
‎我们生活在…
big planet.
‎同一个星球上
A world...
‎一个…
somewhat divided.
‎有些分歧的世界
But we're one.
‎可我们是一体的
And tonight is an example.
‎今晚就是一个例子
Happy. Happy.
‎开心 开心
Happy tears.
‎开心的眼泪
I'm very happy to share in your culture.
‎很开心能感受你们的文化
-Thanks so much. -No, thank you.
‎-非常感谢  ‎-不 是谢谢你们
We are one.
‎我们是一体的
-Yes, we are one. -We are one.
‎-是的 我们是一体的  ‎-我们是一体的
Yes. One tongue, one company.
‎是的 一种语言 一个公司
Yes.
对
Thank you.
‎谢谢
- Aren't watermelons sweet? - Sweet!
‎-西瓜甜不甜  -‎甜
Choose the best picture to put on the cover
‎选一张最好的
of the next edition of Fuyao People!
‎放在下一期"福耀人"的封面上
This is my community,
‎这是我的社区
um, and to see this building come back to life,
‎看到这些建筑恢复生机
it meant a lot to me.
‎对我意义重大
Fuyao is the leader, Fuyao is changing the industry,
‎福耀是领袖 ‎福耀在改变这个行业
and I see us becoming number one in the world next year
我看到 我们正在成为下一个世界第一
and number one in the world every year.
而且每年都会是第一
-Yes, sir. How are you doing? - I have a really good idea for you.
-先生 最近怎么样  -我有个好主意
Why don't you film
‎‎那三个微波炉
those three microwave ovens that have been out for two weeks
都坏了两个星期了还没换
-that haven't been replaced? -Okay.
‎-你怎么不录  ‎-好的
-Why don't you film that? -We will.
‎-你怎么不录那个  ‎-我们会的
And tell me why this area is now gonna be used for production
‎告诉我为什么这要变成车间
and no longer a lunchroom.
不能在这吃饭了
There's signs all over that say that. Where's the lunchroom gonna be?
墙上贴的都是这 ‎那食堂在哪
-I have no clue. You're telling me...  - That's typical.
‎-我不知道 你在跟我说…  ‎-老是这样
You're telling me... telling me something new.
你跟我说… 跟我说点别的吧
I just got back from vacation.
我刚放假回来
They're gonna take all the tables and all the chairs out
‎他们把桌子和椅子都搬出去了
and make this a production space. Like everywhere else.
‎把这弄成车间 跟其他地方一样
I hope they make your office a production space.
‎我希望他们把你的办公室 ‎也弄成车间
They manage to have these things on all the time. This is America.
‎他们一直在播放这些东西 这是美国
We don't need Chinese children singing and praying.
‎我们不需要看中国儿童唱歌玩耍
Coming back from the China trip, uh,
‎从中国回来后
some of the things I started implementing,
‎我开始执行一些事情…
Well, the first thing I implemented was, uh...
‎我落实的第一件事就是…
At our pre-shift meeting,
‎在我们的班前例会
we used to just kind of sit at the tables and talk and...
‎我们习惯坐在桌子上讲话 而且…
watching the Chinese shift meeting, where he had them all lined up...
‎看着中国的班前例会 他们排成队
I've found that that's worked out really well for me back here.
‎我觉得在这里 像他们那样做很好
Good morning, everybody!
‎各位早上好
Greg, I need you to stand on two, starting off.
‎克雷格 你站在第二个 动起来
Chuck, I need you standing on three.
‎查克 你站第三个
I think that's everybody.
大家都来了吧
It's an experiment.
做个实验
So, the lines are running okay today?
‎生产线今天都正常吧
Uh, everybody got your glasses and boots?
‎大家都戴好眼镜 穿好靴子了吗
We're good?
‎好了吗
Any questions?
‎有什么问题吗
Okay, let's have a good day.
‎好的 祝大家今天愉快
- They're gonna do surgery for your hand? - They're gonna tell me tomorrow.
‎-他们会给你的手做手术吗  ‎-他们明天会告诉我的
They'll tell you tomorrow what your recovery's gonna be.
‎他们明天会告诉你 看看你恢复得怎么样
Yeah, they'll probably start at four weeks,
他们可能在四周后开始
determine what... you know, how it's gonna be,
‎确定大概情况
and then, from there, go to the eight weeks.
‎然后 大概就过去八周了
I'm worried about my points.
‎我担心我的工分
-No, no...  - No, no, no, no.
‎-不 不  ‎-不用 不用
Don't worry about any of that.
不用担心
Don't have to worry about your points for missing time.
不用担心工分 或者缺勤
I don't wanna lose my job.
‎我不想失去工作
No, you're not gonna lose your job.
‎不 你不会丢掉工作的
- What's that?  - My pay?
‎-怎么回事 ‎ -那我的工资呢
Yes.
‎有的
It's covered?
还有工资吗
Yes. I don't know how all of that works,
对 不过我不知道具体怎么运行
but it is.
‎不过有工资的
Yeah.
对
Everybody at every level will say we really, really, really want to be safe.
‎各层级的所有人都会说 ‎我们真的只想安安全全的
But safe doesn't pay the bills.
‎可是 安全付不了账单
The room that we work in, there's only one way in,
‎我们这个车间 只有一个入口
no doors on the opposite side.
‎对面没有门
If a fire breaks out,
‎如果发生火灾
that's like being trapped.
我们就会困在这
They're wanting us to pull one of those big sheets off and inspect it.
‎他们想让我们 ‎把这些大玻璃片拆下来检查
Some of this float glass is so big
‎一些浮法玻璃很大
that I'm gonna have people exposing their face,
我不得不让大家把脸露出来
and I don't... I don't need to do that.
我不想... 不想那样
A couple days ago, I had to tell the Chinese fellow
前几天 我跟中国同事说
that I absolutely refuse to pick up two loads with a stand-up forklift.
‎我绝对不会用一个立式叉车去叉两摞玻璃
It's not strong enough.
叉车不够坚固
I said, "If you want to do it, that's fine, you do it. I'm not doing it.
‎我说 "你要做随你 我不干
I'm not... I'm not risking somebody's life."
‎我不会...不会让别人冒生命危险"
Out of all my working life,
我工作了一辈子
I have never ever had a workplace injury, ever.
‎从没受过工伤 从来没有
I mean, 15 years at General Motors,
‎我在通用汽车干了15年
博比
窑炉卸载员
you know, never a workplace injury.
‎从没受过工伤
And then my new job at Fuyao...
‎然后开始在福耀工作…
what happens?
发生什么了呢
I get a workplace injury.
‎我受工伤了
Right now, I'm outside the Moraine plant here,
现在 我站在‎凯特林大道
off of Kettering Boulevard.
莫兰工厂外面
There have been 11 safety complaints filed against Fuyao.
‎这里有十一起针对福耀安全问题的投诉
Some workers claim unsafe working conditions
‎有些工人声称工作条件不安全
and unfair treatment.
‎待遇不公
I say "people," you say "power."
‎我说"人" 你们说"权"
- People! - Power!
‎-人  ‎-权
I say "people," you say "union."
‎我说"工" 你们说"会"
-People! - Union!
‎-工  ‎-会
- People! - Union!
All right!
‎好的
Uh, meeting after work, don't forget, next week.
下班后有集会 别忘了 下周见
We'll see you there. Bring your coworkers.
‎到时候见 把同事带来
There's a lot of information that you're seeing on TV about Fuyao.
‎你们在电视上会看到很多 ‎关于福耀的消息
"Safety concerns,"
‎"安全考量"
um, other things that are... are being reported,
‎还有其他... 相关报道
much of which we do not believe are true.
‎我们认为其中有很多不是真的
'Cause if you bring in a union...
‎因为如果你把工会扯进来…
this becomes illegal.
就样做就违法了
You cannot do it anymore.
你就不能在这继续做下去了
Instead, if I'm an employee,
‎如果我是员工的话
I have to take my concerns to the union rep.
‎我得把自己的想法反映给工会代表
When we had this training in private,
‎上次参加培训的时候 单独他给我们俩培训的时候
I was horrified by this picture.
‎看到这图 真的是很害怕
If this becomes a reality,
也就是说 这张图 产生以后
we wouldn't be able to communicate directly
‎那我们在座的所有人几乎都不能跟美国同事
with our American coworkers.
‎同等直接沟通了
Isn't that terrible?
‎可怕吧
If we are able to improve our management capabilities,
‎这个管理层的素质的提升
it will help quell the union rebellion.
‎有利于平息工会的骚乱
"And if we are able to improve our management capabilities,
‎"如果我们能提升管理层的能力
it will help with our campaign against union organizations..."
‎就能帮助我们开展反对工会的活动…"
We hired Americans to work as our managers and supervisors.
‎我们中国人聘美国人当我们的管理人员
Our expectation was that we could trust them,
‎我们对他们的期待就是 相信他们 你相信他们
pay them a high salary, and they would serve the company.
‎给他们很高的待遇 才会提这个服务 其他没有什么了
Why didn't they?
‎为什么他不做呢
I think they are hostile to Chinese.
‎我觉得 一个是对中国人的一种敌视
The loss from January to October
‎一到十月份的亏损
is about 40 million US dollars.
‎我们这里是录到将近四千万美金
We have to reverse the tide as soon as possible.
把我们过去的经验 用最快的速度扭转过来
With the new restructuring,
‎我相信通过这次的整改
I believe we will see this plant in profit very soon.
‎我很快会看到这里盈利
We've invited Jeff Liu to be our new president.
‎第一个呢 我们请了刘道川先生过来
Uh, good morning, everyone.
‎大家早上好
I was born in 1963, in the Year of the Rabbit.
‎二十七年 我呢 跟大家报告一下 我1963年生 属兔的
I've spent 27 years in the US and 26 years in China.
美国27年 中国26年
People always guess I am in my 40s, but I'm actually 53.
如果别人说的话 大概你四十多岁 我五十三岁
Why is that? Because I have passion.
‎为什么呢 因为我有激情
I have determination to do things well.
‎我要干的事情我要干好
福耀进入下一阶段
汽车玻璃制造商宣布重大改组 ‎总裁和副总裁离职
with company President John Gauthier
‎公司总裁约翰·高蒂尔
and Vice President Dave Burrows leaving."
‎和副总裁戴维·伯罗斯离职
Actually...
‎其实…
terminated.
‎是被停职了
♪ We wish you a Merry Christmas ♪
♪ 祝你圣诞快乐 ♪
♪ And a Happy New Year ♪
♪ 祝你新年快乐 ♪
♪ We wish you a Merry Christmas... ♪
♪ 祝你圣诞快乐 ♪
- Got one. - Got one? All right, boss.
-‎想要一个吗  -好的 老板
Need a hat, Jim?
‎吉姆 要帽子吗
- Right here. I'll take it.  - All right.
‎-过来 我戴  ‎-好了
-That's good, brother.  - Merry Christmas to you.
-很好 哥们  ‎-圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas to you. Thanks for your work.
‎圣诞快乐 ‎感谢辛勤付出
Hello, everybody!
‎大家好
I would like to use this opportunity
‎我想借此机会
to thank each of you for the hard work.
‎感谢大家的辛勤劳动
And also, we need to work as a team
‎同时 我们作为一个团队
under one roof, one culture,
‎在一个屋檐下 感受同一种文化
and make a great year for 2017.
‎成就光辉的2017年
We can turn the company around.
‎我们可以让公司转亏为盈
We make more money, and everybody gonna share the piece of pie.
‎我们赚更多的钱 ‎大家就都能共享更多利润
How's that?
‎觉得怎么样
Good evening.
晚上好
You want a hat, Chairman?
‎董事长 要戴帽子吗
He asked if you want a hat.
‎他问你要不要戴帽子
Of course.
‎当然
Here you go, boss.
‎给 老板
Let me wear a hat.
‎戴上帽子
- Ni hao. -Ni hao, ni hao, ni hao.
-你好  -你好
-Hello. -Ni hao.
Ni hao.
你好
吉尔
叉车操作员
Someone from work was kind enough to tell me
‎公司里有个人很好
that there were these apartments.
‎他告诉我有这样的房子
Four hundred and eighty dollars a month.
‎480块一个月
I fell in love with it.
‎我爱上这了
I can afford to live here
我住得起这里
and have my own place and feel independent again.
‎我能有自己的家 觉得自己独立了
Smells good.
‎味道出来了
This is the most enjoyable moment in a day.
‎这是我最享受的一天 就是这个时候
After I finish the cigarette, my mind just calms down.
‎慢慢抽完之后 心沉下来 然后就开始
We workers lay down tracks
‎我们就像公司里的一个 一个铺导轨的人一样
so the train can run smoothly.
下面的火车你要开
The only thing we have in mind is to do our best.
‎没有说太多顾虑 就是把事情做好 把事情做好
That's true for everyone here.
‎来这边的每个人的想法其实都一样
My wife.
‎我老婆
My toothache has gone.
‎我牙齿都已经好了
They give me so much medicine. I've fully recovered.
‎他们还拿了那么多药 ‎今天已经完全好了
The last time I cried, I was a teenager.
十几岁的时候哭过
And I also cried once after coming here.
来这边流眼泪流过一次 流眼泪
I don't dare mention that to other people.
‎不敢跟别人说
But when all is quiet in the dead of night,
‎夜深人静的时候
I miss my family.
就是想念家人也好 家里有什么事情
I've learned most of what I learned from Leon and Wong.
里昂和王教了我很多东西
None of us knew glass when we came there.
‎我们刚进公司的时候 对玻璃一窍不通
When you get to be my age, not too many people wanna hire you.
‎到了我这把年纪 很少有人会花钱雇我了
They don't wanna take a chance.
‎他们不想冒险
My brother, he's my Chinese brother.
‎我的兄弟 他是我的中国兄弟
I would have his back, just like I'd have one of my own brothers'.
‎我会支持他 ‎就像我会支持自己的兄弟一样
I just... I think the world of him.
‎我...我非常钦佩他
Are you okay?
‎你没事吧
My supervisor started yelling at me.
我主管对我吼
-When... You work at the table right there. -I was working right here just fine.
‎-你在那边的工作台工作  ‎-我之前在那干得好好的
-Now he wanna change it right over here. -We know, the table over there.
‎-现在他想改到这里   -我们知道 那边的工作台
Now, instead of here, they want you to do it here? Okay.
‎不是这里 他们想让你在那里做事
He said he expects us to do eight boxes at a time.
‎他说他想让我们一次操作八箱
I just want to make sure you're not gonna get hurt.
‎我只想确定你不会受伤
He said he want us to push them in here.
‎他想让我们把那些推到这
Well, now, you-- It's probably too heavy for you to push it.
‎可能对你来说有点重 你推不动
-So you need to let him know that. -I don't understand.
‎-你跟他说我推不动  ‎-我不明白
Sometimes, why she don't know to tell that?
‎为什么有时候她不知道说出来
Make sure you're communicating to them that you need help.
‎确保和他们沟通 说你需要帮助
I have.
‎我有啊
He knows.
‎他知道
Rather than trying to find resolution, they try to find out who's wrong.
‎他们不想解决问题 ‎而是想推脱责任
And, in this case, they're both wrong.
‎这个情况 他们都错了
You need some skills to handle Americans.
‎所以对美国人处理要有一些技巧
How can we take advantage of American characteristics
‎就是说 我们怎么能够用他们的优势
to make them work for Fuyao?
‎来能够帮福耀做事情
There's a culture in the US
‎在美国呢 他们的文化是属于
where children are showered with encouragement.
‎从小就是鼓励为主
So everyone who grows up in the US is overconfident.
‎所以每个美国长的孩子 每个美国大人都过于自信
They are super confident.
‎超自信
Americans love being flattered to death.
‎美国这个社会 捧死人不偿命
You will get into trouble if you fight with them.
‎动手打架的话可能会有问题
Donkeys like being touched in the direction their hair grows.
‎实际上中国很多话都是对的 人都是顺毛驴
Right?
‎对吧
You should touch donkeys in the direction their hair grows.
‎驴呢 你顺着它的时候没事
Otherwise, they'll kick you.
‎逆着它 就一定会撂蹶子
Do you understand what I'm saying? You do? Okay.
‎我说话听得懂吧 ‎听得懂啊 好的
We need to use our wisdom to guide them and help them.
‎这个需要咱们的智慧 ‎需要怎么去引导他们 帮助他们
Because we are better than them.
‎因为你比他强
They refer to us as "the foreigners."
‎他们称我们为"老外"
People just want... They wanna feel like they're in America working,
‎人们希望...他们希望觉得自己是在美国工作
not like, when they walk in the door,
‎而不是走进工厂大门
that they've left America and they're now in China.
‎就离开了美国 到了中国
They work nonstop. They're in there all the time.
‎他们毫不停歇 一直工作
Around the clock, 24 hours a day. They're in there on Sundays.
‎全天工作 周日也在那里
There's been some days, they don't want us to take a break for lunch,
‎有时候 他们都不想让我们在吃午饭的时候休息下
because they need X amount of glass out.
‎因为他们需要产出某个数量的玻璃
The Chinese really don't help us out at all.
‎中国人真的完全不帮我们
They just walk around and tell the Americans what to do.
‎他们只是走过来告诉美国人要做什么
"Just do this." And you're like, "Why?"
‎"这么做" 你问 "为什么 "
They don't tell you why at all, and they walk away.
‎他们也不告诉你原因 就转身走了
I know it's a growing company, I know it's new.
‎我知道这是家成长中的公司 ‎是家新公司
But with the workload that comes with it,
‎但随之而来的工作量
you know, you wanna keep your employees around,
‎你是想把员工留住的
especially your good workers.
‎尤其是好员工
A simple pay raise, even if it's just a dollar.
‎简单点的话 涨薪就行 涨一美金也行
Just show your appreciation for them and their hard work.
‎表示你欣赏他们 也感谢他们的辛勤劳动
Optimism, hope. That was what we were all going in with.
‎乐观 希望 ‎这是我们进厂的时候的想法
The future looked bright.
‎前程似锦
Now, it's just... It's a 180.
‎现在是...180度大转弯
To me, it's like they don't respect you.
在我看来 他们不尊重人
At least 3,000 people have come and gone, either fired or quit.
‎至少有三千人来来去去 被炒或辞职
Whenever you have a frustrating day, you can go outside and...
不开心的时候 就出来…
throw your bin over.
‎把垃圾箱掀翻
Every one of our bosses were demoted.
‎我们每个领导都被降职了
- Yeah. - The Chinese are in control.
‎-对  -中国人说了算
Have the Chinese changed their mind?
‎中国人改变主意了吗
Are they not gonna turn this over to us?
‎他们不打算把工厂交给我们了吗
Because that was one of the... definitely that was one of the things
‎因为那是吸引我 绝对是吸引我
that intrigued me about coming here.
‎到这上班的理由之一
I love the fact that they came in here. I love this business.
我欢迎他们来到美国 我喜欢这个行业
I worked at Appleton for over 20 years
‎我在阿普尔顿干了二十多年
and I was one of the guys that got laid off in 2012.
2012年 我成为了一名下岗工人
I've been looking for something for four years.
‎四年来我一直在找事做
I like working with the people on the floor.
‎我喜欢和车间那些人工作
They are working their tails off.
‎他们非常拼命
And they're not getting anything for it,
‎可是他们什么都得不到
and I'm not talking about compensation.
‎我说的不是报酬
They're not getting patted on the back.
没有人鼓励他们
I've seen the Chinese pouring chemicals down the drain
‎我看到一个中国人往码头后面
out the back of our dock.
排水沟倒化学品
Chemicals.
‎化学品
There was a trail of yellow paint going right to the sewer.
‎有一条黄色油漆的痕迹 ‎一直延伸到下水道
- Right out our back door.  - You couldn't miss it.
‎-就在我们的后门那  -一眼就能看见
It... It's like they don't even know what the rules are.
‎就好像...好像他们完全不懂规矩
It's...
‎这个…
And I'm thinking, "This is all going into the sewer
‎我想 "这会进入下水道
and going into drinking water somewhere."
‎流到我们的饮用水源里"
I don't wanna waste your time and I don't wanna to waste my time.
‎我不想浪费你们的时间 ‎也不想浪费我的时间
With what we say at this table,
‎我们坐在这说这些
will it make a difference?
‎有什么用吗
I've asked security to come escort you out if you're going to do that.
‎‎我已经跟保安说过了 如果你再这样他就会过来把你"请"出去
Okay.
‎好的
UNION YES
支持工会
Man, they treat these people like shit in there.
‎他们不把这些人当人看
Sometimes, you gotta be Sally Field.
‎有时候 你得成为莎莉·菲尔德这种倡议工会的人
If there are things your boss can't fix for you, come talk to me.
‎你们有时候 领导没办法的时候可以过来找我
Especially how to manage American workers.
‎特别是对美国人怎么管理
Can we force them to work overtime?
‎可不可以强制让他们加班
- No way! -Not a chance.
-没办法  -没办法
From HR's perspective,
‎从人事的角度上来说
we can't force them to work overtime.
‎我们不能说 可以强制加班
We can't say anything like that.
‎我们不能这样讲的
But in China, it's mandatory.
‎但是 我的意思是说 那边[中国]这是强制性的
The Americans... I don't give a shit what they think.
‎美国呢...我也不管他妈的怎么想的
Go ahead and sue me,
‎你爱告随便告 妈的
but they should come the hell in on Saturdays.
‎但是周六全部都滚进来上班
That's how I would do it.
‎我气成那样 [就会这样做]
I think the most important thing is mutual understanding.
‎我觉得最主要的还是 相互更多人互相去体谅
We're under enormous pressure here.
压力是很大 确实是 说白了
A lot more pressure than in China.
‎在这个地方 比国内压力大好几倍
There was a guy who couldn't fall asleep for a couple of days.
‎那边有个人睡不着 好几天都睡不着
I really admire Americans.
‎很佩服美国人
They can work two jobs.
‎还能上两班倒
They can have another job besides working here.
‎这边上了还能去其它地方
I always thought Americans lived a comfortable and superior life.
‎我还以为他们的生活很优越
I thought they didn't have to make any sacrifices.
不用像 我们想象那样子 去为了生活 失去很多东西
当地汽车工会 696号厅
Good afternoon, everyone.
‎大家下午好
Good afternoon.
‎下午好
All the stories that you've heard about Fuyao is true.
‎你们听到关于福耀的事情都是真的
Just to give you an idea how things are,
‎让你们大致有个了解吧
my daughter does nails for a living.
‎我女儿是做美甲的
Last year, she made $13,000 more than I did.
‎去年她比我多赚一万三
Now, think about that.
‎想想看
She cleared $40,000. I made 27.
‎她赚了四万美金 而我赚了两万七
Something's wrong with that.
‎这样可不对
A coworker of mine was fired
‎我的一位同事被炒了
for being hospitalized for a week and not calling off.
‎因为住院一周  没有请病假
That could've been me. What if I got sick?
这也可能发生在我身上 万一我生病了怎么办
Would they fire me?
‎他们会把我炒掉吗
The man I was working with,
‎跟我一起上班的一个人
the cardboard he was sitting on caught on fire.
‎他坐的纸板箱着火了
And they just kept right on working.
‎他们就那样继续工作
Dayton taxpayers and the state of Ohio have committed
‎代顿的纳税人和俄亥俄州
tens of millions of dollars to Fuyao,
‎给福耀承诺了几千万美元
and yet Fuyao management has failed to provide the good and the safe jobs
‎然而福耀没能为这个社区
that this community deserves.
‎提供社区应得的安全的好工作
Labor.
‎劳工
Working people and the labor movement built America.
‎工人和劳工运动建立了美国
It is what made America great the first time.
‎一开始是这些让美国伟大起来的
The working people at Fuyao right now who don't have a...
‎福耀的工人现在没有…
You have a birthright that's paid for
我们在座的各位
by the sweat and blood of people in this room
‎干活拿钱 天经地义
and people who have gone before people in this room,
在座的各位前辈们
so that you had a right to fair life,
我们有权过上公平的生活
to a workplace that was safe.
‎拥有安全的工作场所
We fought these battles 70 years ago.
‎七十年前 我们做出了反抗斗争
We rejected 70 years ago
七十年前 我们失败了
that management and companies and rich people
‎让那些当官的 公司和有钱人
get to pick and choose
‎来挑挑拣拣
what happens to you or what you get or what you don't get.
‎决定你的命运和所得
Nothing in America has changed
‎对努力工作的人而言
in terms of working people working hard.
‎美国没有什么变化
That's not what changed in America.
‎在美国 这一点没有变
What changed in America was people at the top
‎美国变了的是上面那些人
deciding they wanted to rewrite the rules
‎他们决定改写规则
to take advantage of people.
压榨底层人民
To make it in their favor at your expense.
‎牺牲我们的利益  他们坐收渔翁之利
And you have a right and an obligation to say no to that,
‎你们有权利也有义务拒绝
and that's what unionizing at Fuyao is all about.
‎这就是在福耀成立工会的意义所在
And over the course of fighting for this all these years,
‎在这些年来 奋斗的过程中
we found a way for companies to make money and still be fair to employees,
‎我们为公司找到了一种既能赚钱 ‎又能公平对待员工的方法
and still pay employees a decent wage,
‎还能给员工一份体面的工资
and still make sure that they were safe.
‎而且确保他们的安全
These two things can exist together.
‎这两者是可以共存的
As you fight this fight at Fuyao,
‎你们和福耀的这场战斗
as UAW stands by you and fights that fight with you,
‎汽车工会 会支持你们 和你们一起作战
as we show Fuyao that we do things a little bit different in Dayton, Ohio,
‎我们会让福耀知道 ‎咱们俄亥俄代顿不这么做事
I will be there every step of the way fighting with you,
‎我会和你们并肩战斗
on the side of UAW, on the side of workers,
‎站在汽车工会这边 站在工人这边
and we will win this fight. Thank you.
‎我们会打赢这场战斗 谢谢
- Morning. - Morning.
‎-早上好  ‎-早上好
Next Monday...
‎下周一…
everybody already employed in this room,
‎在场的各位员工
whatever you're paid today, two dollars more.
‎不论时薪多少 一律加薪两块
Thank you.
‎谢谢
Everybody, whatever you make today, two dollars more next Monday.
在座诸位 不论时薪多少 ‎下周一开始 一律加薪两块
Yeah!
‎太棒了
Great?
‎很棒吧
And the people say, "Why are you doing that? We're losing money."
‎人们说 "为什么涨工资 我们在赔钱呢"
The good efficiency generate from the good employee.
高效来自好员工
How do we keep a good employee? Better pay.
‎如何留住好员工呢 更好的待遇
We want to be the best employer in this town. But in return...
‎我们希望成为这里最好的雇主 ‎不过 作为回报…
work hard, work longer.
希望你们努力工作 努力加班
Our team here, we can do the same job as China.
我们在美国工人 不比中国工人差
Raise the bar, and I believe the future will belong to everybody.
对自己要求严格点 ‎我相信未来属于每个人
Thanks again.
‎再次感谢
支持工会
我们支持福耀工人
Victory!
‎胜利
-We are the union! - We are the union!
‎-我们是工会  ‎-我们是工会
-UAW! - UAW!
‎-汽车工会  ‎-汽车工会
They don't want to have to abide by the rules and regulations
‎他们不想遵守美国的
of the United States.
‎规章制度
They're in America, and we want to make sure
‎他们这是在美国 我们想确保
that they abide by the laws in America.
‎他们遵守美国法律
♪ We can bring to birth a new world From the ashes of the old ♪
‎♪ 我们可以在旧世界的废墟上 ‎创造一个新世界 ♪
♪ For the union makes us strong ♪
‎♪ 因为工会使我们强大 ♪
♪ Solidarity forever ♪
‎♪ 永远团结 ♪
♪ 'Cause the union makes us strong ♪
‎♪ 因为工会使我们强大 ♪
♪ Solidarity forever ♪
‎♪ 永远团结 ♪
了解真相!
调派司法人员 汽车工会
We have a better chance of having things done fair
‎如果这些都写在合同里的话
if we have it written out in a contract.
‎我们会做得更好
That's why we need a union.
‎所以我们需要个工会
Management would listen to us because they had to.
‎管理层会听我们的 因为他们必须听
Every job I've ever worked on, being a black woman,
‎作为黑人女性 我打过的每一份工
that's the only way that we have a chance.
‎让我明白 只有这样我们才能有机会
I understand that, at times, there's gonna be a need for a union,
‎我明白 有时候 工会是必要的
but right now, I got a man that's given me a good job,
不过现在 有人能给我提供份好工作
given me a good wage, and allowed me to come to work every day.
工资不错 我每天都能上班
I don't have any need for somebody else to come in and get in the middle of this.
‎我不想有人横插一脚 坏了我的好事
The only thing the union's gonna do is keep the bad workers.
‎工会唯一会做的 就是留下烂员工
And the good workers, it's just gonna go along like it is for us.
‎而像我们这样的良好员工 都只随大流
How's that work for me?
对我有什么好处
持续发声
投反对票
你知道吗?
福耀提供很好的福利待遇 靠付工会费得不到的
投反对票
I know there are some union activists here.
‎‎我都会知道 他们这几个极端个别的工会头目
I know because
‎我会知道
I have people who spy for me.
因为我在下面 班组里面有我的耳目
I have many different ways to deal with them.
‎‎我对付这些工会的办法五花八门
Here is one. He is pro-union.
‎这个也是工会的
This is him. This person here.
‎就是这个
Look, we get along pretty well.
‎你看 我跟他 我跟他会很好
You won't see him here in two weeks' time.
‎你 再过两周过来 就没有这个人了
(LRI培训 LRI即劳资关系研究所)
Good afternoon.
‎下午好
I want to thank you so much for coming.
‎非常感谢大家能够过来
I know you didn't have a choice.
‎我知道你们别无选择
(福耀员工录音)
The union will go out of their way
‎工会会竭尽全力
to try to convince you that it's a good thing for you
‎试图说服你们 说这对你们是好事
and that it is in your best interest.
‎符合你们的最大利益
The contract that you get,
‎你们得到的合同
if you get one,
‎如果你们能得到的话
might include better wages and benefits.
‎可能包含更好的工资和福利
That contract might include the same wages and benefits you have today.
合同可能包含你今天拥有的 ‎工资和福利
And that contract finally might include less wages and less benefits.
‎‎合同最后也可能包含 ‎更少的工资和福利
And the threat of a strike is no longer scary to employers,
‎罢工的威胁 对雇主来说没那么可怕
because today if you go on strike, while you can't get fired,
‎因为今天 如果你们罢工 ‎又不能炒掉你们的话
the employer has the right to permanently replace you.
‎雇主有权永久把你换掉
I'll let that sink in.
‎你们好好想想
You can't get fired for going on strike, but you can get permanently replaced.
‎罢工不会被炒掉 但是会被永久换掉
So are you telling us not to vote for the union?
‎你是来跟我们说 别给工会投票吗
I'm here to tell you to do what you want.
‎我来这跟你们说 做自己想做的事
I got a question. Who do you work for?
‎我有个问题 你给谁干活
I work for a company called Labor Relations Institute.
‎我效力于一家 名叫"劳资关系研究所"的公司
We're a labor consulting firm.
‎我们是劳资咨询公司
- Is the company paying you? - Yes.
‎-公司付你钱吗  ‎-是的
Didn't I say that? I usually say that in every meeting.
‎我没说吗 我通常每次开会都说的
- No. - No, you didn't say that yet.
‎-没  -对 你还没说
Well, the reality is, they pay me to consult with you here...
‎事实就是… ‎他们付钱让我和你们商量…
They pay you to talk to us?
‎他们付钱让你和我们谈话
They pay me. They don't pay me enough to stand up here and lie to you.
‎他们给我付钱 ‎但金额不足以让我站在这对你们撒谎
Okay?
‎好吗
强制会议
第一场 周二 三楼
He says that he was being impartial, but he wasn't.
‎他说他是公正的 但并没有
The UAW is free to use everywhere else in the world.
‎世界上其他任何地方都会采纳汽车工会
迈卡
福耀律师
If they want to pay our... pay our workforce
‎如果他们想付钱给我们的工人
to sit through a presentation, to listen to the pitch,
‎让他们坐那听讲座 听那个讲话
that's their right.
‎那是他们的权利
But while they're on our clock, it's our message.
‎但如果在我们的工作时间 ‎就得由我们说了算
They spent a lot of money to bring these people in here
‎他们花了很多钱 把工人聚到这
to make sure that every employee
‎确保每个员工
goes through this session,
‎都听完讲座
not once, but twice, maybe three times.
‎不是一场 而是两场 可能三场
They have people walking around there with patches and stickers on
‎他们给到处走来走去的工人身上贴上纸条
that's saying: "Vote no.
‎写着 "投反对票
You still have a voice."
‎你依然有发言权"
Now, my question to them people are:
‎现在我想问这些人
What voice do you have?
‎你们有什么发言权
When have you ever had a voice?
‎你们什么时候有过发言权
福耀向LRI支付一百万 ‎对抗工会
自1970年代起 反工会咨询业 稳步发展 平均工资和工会会员随之减少
Ever since they started this job, it's been a two-man job.
‎他们设立这个岗位的时候 ‎就是两个人的工作
When they put me out here on it,
‎他们让我来干
they decided they wanted it to be a one-person job.
‎他们希望一个人就能干完
When I went to talk to HR, I told them they were targeting me.
‎我去找人力资源谈话 ‎我告诉他们 这是在针对我
Put me on a job to set me up to write me up for performance issues
‎给我挖坑 然后打报告说我绩效不行
and fire me.
‎接着炒了我
吉尔·拉曼蒂亚 不得进入厂区
持续发声 投反对票
I got the phone call from Fuyao
‎我接到福耀的电话
that they had fired me.
他们要炒了我
I really truly feel like... that they targeted me.
‎我真的觉得...他们针对我
I was on the news, I was at the city council meetings.
‎我上了新闻 参加了市议会会议
It's been a pretty sad...
‎我真的很伤心…
工作保障
few days.
好几天
This sinking feeling of...
这种失落的感觉…
"I don't have a job."
‎"我失业了"
I mean, I'm a good worker.
‎我是个好员工
Workers union!
‎工会
Should I have gotten so involved?
‎我应该这么投入吗
Put my whole life into it?
‎整个人生都押上去吗
Here's old Fuyao.
‎这是福耀老厂
Can't spell Fuyao without F-U.
‎不说F-U就拼不出福耀
When I was at Fuyao, I didn't think we needed a union.
我在福耀的时候 没想过我们需要工会
Move forward to today, you have no voice, you have...
‎时至今日 你没有发言权了… 你...
Truly, you...
‎‎真的 你…
From what I'm told, there really isn't an American with authority
‎据我所知 他们真的找不到一个 有权威的美国人
that they can talk to.
‎可以说得上话
You know, I...
‎你知道吗 我…
I think these employees need something.
‎我觉得这些员工有需求
I think I need to make only two more trips this year,
我们‎今年下半年 我想再来两次就行了
if you achieve what you planned.
你们 你们跟上进度计划 我就不要
Why do I need to come here? It's not convenient for me. Right?
‎不要让我辛苦了 跑过来干嘛  ‎你说是不是
You think I like to come to America every month?
‎你认为我喜欢每个月跑过来啊
It's tiring.
‎累死了
Is the union making any noise?
‎最近工会没有声音了是不是
No, not too much.
‎基本上比较小了
Better than it was before.
‎比之前好
Recently, we fired a lot of union supporters.
‎最近有目标地淘汰了很多工会的人
We have tried different ways. It's worked out.
‎做了很多这种措施 还是很有效的
A lot of active ones left...
‎好多人走了...
Then you guys should hire more excellent people.
‎后面就招一些优秀的人进来
Young people.
‎年轻的
This is the culture I want for our company.
‎培养这样一个文化
Then we will have a good atmosphere here.
‎要把这个局面巩固下来
A lot of things here in the US are different from China.
‎美国很多东西 它确实是 跟中国的方法不太一样
Well, we've invested here already. It's just not working that well.
‎谁叫 我在这里投资 投资了 他就是不行
投赞成票
汽车工会
Morning, y'all.
‎大家早上好
-Fired up, ready to vote. -Ready to win!
‎-火力全开  ‎-准备获胜
-Ready to vote. -Ready to win.
‎-准备投票  ‎-准备获胜
-Ready to win! -There you go.
‎-准备胜利  ‎-很好
-You ready to win. - All right, girl!
‎-准备获胜  ‎-好的 姑娘
Fired up, ready to win!
‎火力全开 准备获胜
These are actually people from the United Auto Workers Union,
‎这些是汽车工会的人
and they're out here demonstrating, trying to encourage Fuyao employees
‎他们来这里示威 试图鼓励‎福耀员工
to vote "yes."
投赞成票
Fuyao released a statement earlier
‎福耀早前发布声明
saying that they believe the United Workers Union is corrupted
‎说他们认为美国工会腐败
and they hope that the workers vote "no."
‎他们希望工人投"反对票"
More than 1,500 workers are expected...
‎预计有一千五百多名工人…
We all have a psychological shadow.
‎大家有个阴影
Fuyao doesn't want to be controlled by the union.
‎福耀不想被工会掌控着
As the Chinese saying goes,
‎中国有句俗话叫作
"One mountain cannot hold two tigers."
‎"一山容不下二虎"
Voting just ended an hour ago.
‎投票一小时前结束了
Now the National Labor Relations Board is counting those votes inside the plant
‎现在 美国劳资关系委员会在厂里计票
with both Fuyao and UAW watching...
‎福耀和汽车工会都在看着…
Yes!
太棒了
We won by a landslide.
‎我们完胜 我们是完胜
We won 60%?
‎我们百分之六十啊
Right.
‎对啊
We're awesome!
‎那我们就太牛逼啦
868 noes, 444 yes.
‎868反对 444支持
Yeah.
‎对
就是这样
I wasn't shocked...
‎我不吃惊…
because I know the... the young people got scared.
‎因为我知道他们 年轻人怕了
Them LRI people scared the shit out of 'em, that's all.
劳资关系研究所的人把我们吓死了 就这样
Before we started having those trainings,
‎我们参加那些培训之前
I felt like there was a big "yes" vote.
‎我觉得很可能都是投赞成票的
They spoke a lot about a strike,
‎他们说了很多罢工的事
and like, not being able to be paid, unless we... You know.
‎拿不到工资 除非我们…你懂的
So, I feel like people, you know, are worried about their income.
所以 ‎我觉得 人们担心自己的收入
'Cause I definitely was, you know? So...
‎因为我肯定担心 所以…
There you have it. Overwhelming no.
‎好了 压倒性的反对
Good morning, everyone.
‎大家早上好
Morning.
早上好
Last night I couldn't sleep
我昨晚没睡着
because I feel...
‎因为我觉得…
even more heavier burden on my shoulder.
‎肩上的担子更重了
You guys gave me a chance
‎你们给了我一个机会
to make FGA better.
‎让福耀美国更好
My goal is gonna work with the team to make sure
‎我的目标是和团队合作
every single issue I cannot resolve overnight,
确保一出现问题 ‎如果一晚上解决不了
but give me some time.
‎那就花更多时间解决
Can we do this?
‎我们能做到吗
Yeah?
‎可以吗
All right, one more thing: life is short.
‎好了 还有一件事 人生苦短
We're gonna select the best ten employees go to China.
‎我们要选出最优秀的十个员工去中国
There's some pictures.
‎这有些照片
This is Shanghai.
‎这是上海
Shanghai is the most modern city in China.
‎上海是中国现代化最快的城市
Look like Manhattan, right?
‎看起来像曼哈顿吧
It's like a Manhattan too.
‎本身也像曼哈顿
Yeah, this is a Hyatt Hotel. Hyatt Hotel.
‎这是凯悦酒店 凯悦酒店
They have a sky pool, 55 floor.
‎有无边游泳池 五十五层屋顶
You swim in the sky.
‎你可以在天上游泳
And I'm gonna share the good news for you.
‎我要跟你们分享这个好消息
One of you lucky guys,
‎你们当中的一个幸运儿
you're gonna see that city.
‎可以去参观这座城市
We're one Fuyao, one family.
‎我们是一个福耀 一家人
We create the miracle.
‎我们创造奇迹
We need to create success forever.
‎我们需要永远创造成功
Let's make American great again.
‎我们让美国再次强大
The smooth operation of our US project
‎美国项目的顺利投产
has laid a solid foundation for our global strategy.
‎为我们福耀全球战略打下了坚实基础
We've achieved double-digit growth in operation management.
‎在经营管理上实现了 ‎两位数的稳健增长
Both our earnings and profits have reached new digits.
‎收入和利润双双创历史新高
The China of my youth was poor
‎当我在 生活在过去的
and undeveloped.
‎那个落后的中国时
I feel I was happier then.
‎我倒觉得很快乐
Now I live in a new era
‎但我今天跨入现在这个社会来的时候呢
of prosperity and modernity,
虽然现代化 各方面物质基本都上来了
but I have a sense of loss.
‎但是总有一种很大的失落
I miss the croaking frogs and chirping bugs of my childhood.
‎就是我很难回到 原来的那个蝉叫蛙鸣的那个时代
The wild flowers blooming in the field.
‎看着田野上的鲜花小草
In the past few decades, I have built so many factories.
‎在这几十年里 我拼命开工厂的时候
Have I taken the peace away and destroyed the environment?
‎是不是把环境给破坏了呢 这个原本很安宁的地方 变得不安宁了
I don't know if I am a contributor or a sinner.
‎我自己弄不清楚到底是有功之人 ‎还是有罪之人 不清楚
But...
那…
I only think that way when I'm unhappy.
‎如果不是心情不好 就不会这样想
The point of living is to work.
‎人嘛 活着就是要干活
Don't you think so?
‎你说是不是
Last Friday, I was terminated from Fuyao
‎上周五 我被福耀炒了
after two and a half years.
‎干了两年半
The excuse given was I was too slow pulling up something on the computer.
‎给我的理由是 我操作电脑动作太慢
Took me about two or three minutes.
‎我花了两或三分钟
It wasn't quick enough.
‎不够快
I wouldn't take away the last two and a half years.
‎我不会忘记过去的两年半
I met a lot of good friends
‎我遇到到很多好朋友
and I learned a lot from the Chinese.
‎我从中国人身上学到了很多
I don't have any food for you.
‎没东西给你吃啦
I have some watermelon in my apartment.
‎去我家吃西瓜吧
I don't think he can eat fruit.
‎水果应该不能吃
He can eat grass.
‎它能吃草
- Take care, guys. - See you later.
‎-你们保重  ‎-回头见
- Bye, Wong. -Bye-bye.
‎-再见 王  ‎-拜拜
In the old days, all Chinese people wanted in life
最早以前 吃饱饭 然后把家里
was to have enough food and to raise their kids.
就是孩子抚养成人
That's all they wanted.
‎这个是中国人一辈子做的
When it comes to my generation, we want it all.
‎到了我这一辈之后呢 通吃
We travel wherever we want and buy whatever we like.
‎想去哪里玩就去哪里玩 想买什么东西就买什么东西
GM afforded me a great life...
‎通用给了我很好的生活..
that was cut off
‎他们关闭的时候
when they closed the doors.
‎这一切就没了
We will never ever make that type of money again.
‎我们再也赚不到那种钱了 永远没了
Those days are over.
‎那些日子结束了
There you go!
‎很好
All right!
‎好的
Well, I didn't even know.
‎我都不知道
You never give up on the American dream.
‎你永远不会放弃美国梦
To me, that would be un-American.
‎对我来说 那就太没有美国范儿了
I can have that white fence.
‎我能有白色篱笆
I can have that nice home.
‎我能有漂亮屋子
Send my children to college if that's what they want to do.
‎如果孩子愿意 就送他们上大学
Get treated with common decency.
‎被人以礼相待
You have to be able to believe in it.
‎你必须有这样的信念
We used to have one person here.
‎这边本来有一个人
Now we don't have anyone.
‎我这边都没人了
Next, I'm going to get rid of four workers here.
‎我下次要做的就是把这四个人取消掉
Two for each line.
‎每一条线的两个人取消掉
Automation means standardization.
‎自动化就是要标准化
After we finish this,
‎这个做完以后
we will have two fewer workers uploading on the encapsulation line.
‎包装和上片的两个人就没有掉了
The mechanical arms do that instead.
‎可以用机械臂来操作
You have already finished that?
‎这个已经做完了吧
Yes. These are all automatic.
‎做完了 都是自动的
And you're replacing the rest with mechanical arms too?
‎很快其它的都改成机械作业
Yes. I will replace the ones on side-window tempering.
嗯 ‎我把钢化厂边窗的先改掉
This one is being tested now.
‎现在在做验证
We're hoping to cancel four workers in July or August.
‎我们希望七 八月份的时候 ‎把这些人去掉
I'll change that into machine work.
‎我改成机器在这边磨
We can't get the work done now. They are too slow.
‎现在没办法 因为他们太慢了
截至2030年 因为自动化 ‎导致全球高达三亿七千五百万人 需要寻找全新种类的工作
员工 政府以及企业如何解决这个问题 会重新定义未来的工作
福耀美国公司从2018年开始盈利
起薪仍为每小时14美元
该公司现在约有两千三百名美国工人和两百名中国工人